To close this lesson out,
在本章课程结束之前
I want to make a quick reminder that feature engineering is
我想提醒一下 特征工程也是
an option when performing an investigation into your data.
探索数据的一种方式
In this video, I'm going to look an example of biases in Pokemon creatures statistics.
这个视频中 我们来看一下精灵宝可梦数据中的一个有关偏差的例子
More specifically, I want to know if
更具体地说 我想知道
a creature's offensive stats are biased towards physical or special-attack,
如果一个角色的防守数据偏向物理防御 (defense) 或特殊防御 (special-defense)
if their defensive stats are similarly biased towards physical or special defense.
那么它的进攻数据是否也会偏向物理攻击 (attack) 或特殊攻击 (special-attack)
To do this, I will create new variables based on ratios.
为了探索该问题 我创建了一个基于比例的新变量
The attack ratio column is the ratio between attack and special-attack.
akt_ratio 是 attack 和 special-attack 这两个变量的比例
If a creature has a value greater than one,
如果这个值大于1
then they favored the physical side,
那它更偏向物理攻击 (attack)
and if less than one, they favor the special sides.
如果小于 1 则更偏向特殊攻击 (special-attack)
I do the same thing for the defensive statistics.
对防守的统计数据 我也用同样的方法
The basic scatter plot looks like this.
基本的散点图长这样
Let's polish things up by adding
让我们在图里加入一些透明度
some transparency and then changing the axis scales to log scales.
并对坐标轴做对数变换
That way a bias of two to one is evenly spaced from
这样 不管是在物理方向还是在特殊方向上
the even ratio of one in both the physical and special directions.
偏差在坐标轴上都是均等分布的 (比如物理方向的 2 倍与特殊方向的 0.5 倍是均等的)
Next, I'll add some tick marks appropriate for a log scale.
接下来 添加适合 log 比例的刻度线
Finally, I'll set the axis limits to remove the extreme outliers.
最后 通过设置坐标轴范围将异常值移除
These particular limits also centered the plot on one on both axes.
这个限制 也将两个坐标轴都设置为 1 为中心点
In the final plot, we see that most points seem to fall along a diagonal line.
在最后的图表中 我们看到所有的数据基本上都落在对角线附近
In the upper right-hand quadrant,
在右上方的象限中
we have Pokemon species that are physical biased in both offense and defense,
这些宝可梦在防守和进攻方面都偏向物理方向
and in the lower left-hand quadrant,
在左下方的象限中
they are special biased in both offense and defense.
它们在防守和进攻方面都偏向特殊方向
Interestingly, there appears to be a large number of Pokemon
有趣的是 从 y = 1 这条线上可以看出
on the y equals one line showing no defensive bias.
似乎有大量的宝可梦 它们并没有防守偏向
These Pokemon have a wide range of offensive biases.
但攻击偏向差异很大
There appeared to be much fewer Pokemon on the x
而在 x = 1 这条线上
equals one line showing no offensive bias.
只有很少的宝可梦 它们没有攻击偏向
Findings like these would be difficult to come by and
如果没有做特征工程
summarize if we didn't build our engineered features.
很难得到这样的结论